Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
[Strange Tales of Tang Dynasty III:
To Chang'an]
[Episode 35]
Who discovered the body first?
I did.
Suchan,
the dead cannot be brought back to life.
Now, the priority
is to find the killer,
so as to let Mr. Geng
rest in peace.
There is no killer.
What?
Have you examined the body?
No, I haven't even touched it.
But according to
what my father taught me a few days ago,
the state of his body was caused
by strychnine poisoning.
And strychnine...
is exactly what my father
took to relieve the pain from sores.
I've observed the scene
and found no signs of struggle.
So, I can conclude
that my father
died of an overdose of strychnine.
I've heard about
strychnine poisoning,
but never seen it happen before my eyes.
Strychnine is a medicinal material
that reduces swelling and relieves pain.
However, it's not commonly seen,
because patients
can be easily poisoned by it,
if it's used without caution.
Once the toxins kick in,
the affected will be in extreme agony.
Their bodies will bend into a rigid arch,
with their heads and feet drawing close,
resembling looms.
This is why it's also called
"the loom poison."
Those poisoned by strychnine
will first experience fatigue
and neck stiffness.
Then,
spasms will occur
in their shoulders and thighs,
followed by full-body convulsions.
In the end, their bodies will bend
into bow-like arches.
This last phase
will repeat multiple times.
It's fair to say this is the worst pain
in the human world.
Based on that what you said,
Mr. Geng was exactly poisoned
by strychnine.
Let me in!
Mentor!
Sheriff Su,
how did my mentor die?
Has his body been examined?
Not yet.
We suspect
that he consumed too much strychnine,
which resulted in fatal poisoning.
That's impossible.
My mentor
had a good knowledge of medicine.
He knew strychnine is highly toxic.
How could he have taken an overdose of it?
Could it be that he didn't
want to live anymore,
given the excruciating pain from sores?
Sometimes people just
lose the will to live
in an instant.
Nonsense!
My mentor endured many hardships
all his life.
What hadn't he been through?
How could he have
possibly taken his own life
due to the unbearable pain from sores?
-What do you think you're doing?
-Senior Yin!
Hands off!
Sheriff Su,
please allow me, Yin Yao,
to examine my mentor's body,
so as to find the real murderer.
I'll allow it.
Suchan,
assist him.
Yes.
[The final chapter:
Why coroners must not kill]
[Volume 17 of The Autopsy Chronicles]
[Geng Residence]
Su Wuming.
I think it's time we issued a notice.
People should be advised not to
pick up life-borrowing pouches again,
if they see any in the streets,
especially at intersections.
This act will cause nothing but panic.
I've spent a long time
studying the 6 characters
written on the note
inside the life-borrowing pouch
found by that beggar.
The only thing I'm certain of
is that it must haven't been long
since the writer
began learning penmanship.
Mentor!
The autopsy is complete.
Yin Yao now believes his mentor
committed suicide.
My condolences to both of you.
It's time you set up
a mourning hall for Mr. Geng.
Sir,
everyone,
Suchan,
while you're all here,
I'd like to make an announcement.
I owe Mentor a debt of profound gratitude.
Nothing disappointed him
more in his life than my choice
to change my profession.
In Suchan's presence,
he asked me
to co-author
The Autopsy Chronicles
with him,
and return to being a coroner,
bearing that identity.
I didn't agree to it at that time.
But now that I think of it,
he was basically using his life
as leverage.
It was I who caused my mentor's death.
Today,
before my mentor's spirit in heaven,
I call upon all here to witness
that I, Yin Yao,
will work as a coroner again
and stay in this profession forever.
I will also sign up
for the upcoming Coroners' Contest.
I swear to win the championship,
so that the title of "the best coroner"
will perpetually
belong to my master's school.
Great. That's good news.
Su Wuming,
despite Mr. Geng's sudden death,
Yin Yao's return to the coroner profession
is great news.
Shouldn't you be happy?
Didn't Mr. Geng tell you
that given Yin Yao's talent,
he would surely become the best coroner?
Mr. Yin,
I believe
what you just said
would bring peace
to Mr. Geng's soul.
But now, the urgent matter
is to quickly set up a mourning hall.
Are you Mr. Yin?
I'm so grateful to you
for tidying up my father's appearance,
thus making
his passing particularly dignified.
Thank you so much.
I was only doing my job.
How much is this box of makeup supplies
of mine worth?
Show me what's inside.
Are you selling them all?
Yes.
There are indeed many items.
Some are truly good stuff.
I'll offer...
2,000 coins.
I ask for 3,000 coins.
How about 2,300?
3,000 at least.
They were used
by the one and only mortician in Chang'an.
After today,
there won't be morticians here anymore.
These makeup tools are for the dead?
Then...
Who will know that if neither of us tell?
If this entire makeup kit
were for the living,
you would be charged 6,000 coins at least.
Will you take it for 3,000 coins or not?
Yes, sure.
You're back.
There are 3,000 coins.
Take them.
I sold my makeup kit.
Senior Yin,
I know that makeup kit
was all you owned.
Why are you giving me all your money?
[Funeral]
Mentor,
I, Yin Yao,
offer to give Suchan a lifetime of care.
Now, I'm begging for your consent
to let me marry her!
Senior Yin,
I never thought
you loved me.
Why would you say that?
Because you moved out.
I moved out...
so that one day
I could come back for an eternal stay.
That doesn't sound right.
[Funeral]
This house...
is too old and shabby.
Also, it's eery and creepy here.
The future best coroner in the nation
will work in the county office.
He will be revered by all,
and his descendants
can pursue scholarly honors.
Therefore,
we should move to
a brighter and more spacious mansion.
Are you so sure
you will win the Coroners' Contest?
I wasn't that sure before.
But now,
as long as I offer The Autopsy Chronicles
that Mentor and I wrote together
to the county office,
will anyone dare
deny me the title of "the best coroner"?
Senior Yin,
Father would prefer
for you to earn a place in the top three
through your own effort.
Suchan,
actually,
you are not
Mentor's daughter.
What?
In all his life time,
Mentor only took one wife.
By the time Zhong Shizai
became Mentor's student,
[In loving memory of
my father Geng Wushang]
she had passed away.
I am an orphan Mentor adopted.
As for you...
you were an abandoned baby he took in.
We came from similar places of pain.
I promise you
a lifetime of care
and a life better than most others'.
You won't have to work
as a coroner anymore.
Just bear
and raise children for me at home.
Regrettably,
the last chapter of The Autopsy Chronicles
hasn't been finished.
Nonetheless,
as co-author,
I've come up with proper content for it.
I'll write about
how a coroner
should work with the constables
and make achievements
in a county office setting.
[Fair and Impartial]
Sir,
three murders happened in a row,
yet the killers haven't been caught.
According to protocol,
the case should be handed over
to Yongzhou Prefecture Office.
No need to rush.
Has the mourning hall
for Mr. Geng been set up yet?
Yes, it's all set.
Yin Yao said he had chosen a proper day—
Mr. Geng's burial is today.
Mr. Geng's burial is today?
Yingtao,
make an arrest.
[Geng Residence]
Begin the funeral procession!
Hold on!
I, Wannian County Sheriff, Su Wuming,
am here to examine Mr. Geng's body.
Those unrelated to the matter, step back!
Sir,
Senior Yin and I
already examined the body yesterday.
Since Mr. Geng was your next of kin,
the autopsy you conducted
wasn't a proper procedure.
I've decided to re-examine his body.
The dead deserve respect.
My mentor's body is already in the coffin.
Are you going to open it?
Mr. Geng worked as a coroner all his life.
He must've opened quite a lot of coffins
for case investigations.
A coroner's family is making excuses
to stop a coffin from being opened.
That's beyond ridiculous.
All of you, leave.
I'd like to pay my respects to Mr. Geng.
[Wannian County Office]
What are the autopsy results, Sheriff Su?
Didn't
my mentor die of
strychnine poisoning?
Yes, he did.
Are there scratch marks on his hands,
arms, neck, or face?
No.
Any signs of struggle or resistance?
None.
That is to say,
my mentor
consumed the strychnine himself,
instead of being forced
to take it.
Correct.
Then what was the point
of opening his coffin
to examine his body?
That was utter disrespect to my mentor.
I'll report you!
Report me?
I'm afraid
you won't have a chance to do so.
I found this...
on Mr. Geng's body.
[Notice of Expulsion for Zhong Shizai]
You were filial to him.
[Witnesses: Suchan, Yin Yao]
Mr. Geng also valued you.
[Fair and Impartial]
But when he realized
you might be a murderer,
he hid the evidence
somewhere against his skin
and then ended his own life
with strychnine.
He hoped his despair and death
would end your killing spree.
What are you talking about?
I don't understand.
There's a brush and ink.
Do you dare to write the characters
of one, three, and six?
What do you mean?
Why should I write anything?
Sounds about right.
You're on guard now.
Even if you do as I say,
your writing won't tell anything.
The brilliant Mr. Geng
thought ahead about that.
Write the date down.
June twenty-third.
[June twenty-third]
[Three]
Expelling a disciple
requires signatures from fellow disciples.
That's an unprecedented rule.
Mr. Geng just made that up,
so he could see your handwriting.
How could that be possible?
My mentor was a mere coroner.
A coroner though he was,
he figured out
that Dong Yue's death
was connected to Zhong Shizai
before I did.
Xijun,
compare the handwriting on the note
within the life-borrowing pouch
with that on this document.
Yes.
[Fair and Impartial]
Yin Yao,
it really was you.
Why?
Did you truly care for my father,
or were you afraid that he'd die
before the completion
of The Autopsy Chronicles?
Su Wuming.
What have I done
to deserve your suspicion?
I'm the co-author
of The Autopsy Chronicles.
I'll offer this book to the court.
I'll become
the best coroner
and leave my name in history!
As I said,
you won't have a chance to do so.
Now, look at this.
[Yin Yao is not allowed
to work as a coroner again]
That can't be true.
During the three years I was away,
Mentor was drowned in regrets.
He meant to compensate me
by inviting me
to put my name
on The Autopsy Chronicles.
That day, despite the flattering words
he said about morticians,
I was well aware
that he actually wanted me
to return to the coroner profession
and to bring honor to our school.
Mr. Geng already decided
the title of the final chapter
of the last volume
of The Autopsy Chronicles.
[The final chapter:
Why coroners must not kill]
It's called "why coroners must not kill."
I also found it hard
to understand the title,
judging from it alone.
But after seeing this note,
I figured it out.
Mr. Geng actually dropped a hint.
[Yin Yao is not allowed
to work as a coroner again]
[The final chapter:
Why coroners must not kill]
You're not allowed
to work as a coroner again
exactly because
you killed.
In fact,
you've already given yourself away.
When Dong Yue's disciple died,
behind his body,
a square area on the floor
was not tainted by blood.
That happened
because of what you call
"the mortician's ritual," right?
No one else knows I'm here to tidy up
Dong Yue's appearance, right?
Right.
I know my mentor and your school
were on bad terms.
So...
Thank you for coming here, Mr. Yin.
What is this for?
The mortician's ritual,
a ceremony that the deceased deserve.
How may I help?
Stand in front of me.
Do as I do.
Turn around to face the door.
Pray for your mentor.
Keep the posture.
Close your eyes.
It was midnight.
The night watchman
must've passed by the coffin shop.
Out of fear of being discovered,
you fled in panic,
and didn't have time
to wipe the blood on the floor,
thus leaving evidence behind.
Comparison completed.
The handwriting
attributed to Yin Yao on this document
and that on the note
within the life-borrowing pouch
are from the same person.
Mr. Geng was a wise man.
I'm sure
he wouldn't have poisoned himself
if he hadn't found solid evidence.
At the thought of that,
I opened his coffin for an autopsy.
Just as I expected,
in his bosom, he did hide a note
that you wrote on
when you were off guard.
I should've been more careful.
I saw that document
when I examined his body.
I meant to have it buried with him
under the ground,
so no one would ever know
that I was the one borrowing lifespan.
When I write again,
I'll change that stupid writing habit.
Why did you
do all that?
Mentor adopted me when I was little.
But I really hope
I had a different adopter.
His face was full of wrinkles,
with gloomy looks in his eyes.
He dealt with dead bodies all day long.
I feared him so much.
I wanted to learn to read and write,
but he made me learn
how to examine dead bodies.
He even told me
that a coroner's knowledge
was passed down orally,
so there was no need to become literate.
However, later on,
he taught Suchan to read and write.
I found him repulsive,
but I knew I'd starve
to death if I left him.
Then, gradually,
I took a liking to
deal with dead people.
I realized I have a gift for it.
Meanwhile, he was
exploiting my talent.
It would be
more accurate to say
I was half a mentor to him,
than to say
he was my mentor,
because it was I who first came up with
the Open-Pit Bone Steaming Method.
Three years ago,
he wrote all that
into The Autopsy Chronicles,
which deeply upset me.
Writing it into the book was equal
to claiming that method as his invention.
Not a word about me
would be recorded.
Besides,
when the Ministry of Justice
and the Court of Judicial Review
asked him to recommend a coroner,
he always opted for Zhong Shizai.
He even said Zhong Shizai
was adept
in both literature and martial arts,
praising him as a rare all-around talent.
That just nurtured more hatred in me!
If he thought that way,
why didn't he teach me
how to read and write
and shape me into a well-around talent?
In the past three years,
you not only learned to write,
but also studied martial arts,
judging from the force
of your sword strike.
I don't know martial arts.
But I'm very strong.
Every night, steeped in hatred,
I practiced stabbing and slashing
with all my might.
I'm not a fool.
I changed professions
only to provoke guilt in him.
I knew him well.
All his life, he cared about nothing
but passing down his autopsy skills.
Zhong Shizai was eager for quick success.
He would get in trouble sooner or later.
I was waiting for that day.
When that happened,
in order to persuade me to return
to the coroner profession,
my mentor would definitely make a gesture.
He would either
let me inherit The Autopsy Chronicles,
or give me
the recognition
I deserved—
the co-author of this book!
I waited three years.
This day nearly didn't arrive,
because his sores flared up
and he might die anytime.
Then I remembered
a case we worked on
when I was young.
A merchant borrowed lifespan
for his father.
You know what?
Though the merchant
was cut in half at the waist,
his father did
manage to live several more years.
So,
I decided to borrow lifespan too.
I needed my mentor to stay alive
till The Autopsy Chronicles was finished!
I must rise to fame with this book's help!
[Fair and Impartial]
How can an evil creature
like you work as a coroner?
It's important to have talent,
but one's nature matters most!
Yin Yao,
you will receive severer punishment
than your senior Zhong Shizai did.
You will pay for the deaths
of those three innocent people
with your own life.
[In loving memory of
my father Geng Wushang]
That night,
Father asked me a question.
Suchan,
if you attended the Coroners' Contest
on behalf of me and your fellows,
and the examiner asked you
why coroners must not kill,
what would be your answer?
Coroners must not kill...
Some may say
this is stating the obvious,
because no one
should take another's life.
[Speak and Seek Truth]
But that's the code of conduct
for coroners.
Here's the first reason.
Coroners are accustomed to seeing corpses
and murder scenes.
They're usually numb when looking at
the horrific scenes
where killings have happened.
Coroners also know a lot about the weapons
and methods used for murder.
Therefore, it has to be emphasized
that coroners must not kill,
or they could become bloodthirsty fiends.
Second,
if coroners kill and examine bodies,
the truth will be buried forever.
Third,
a coroner's duty
is to reveal the truth
and serve justice.
If coroners kill,
what will people
think of this profession?
When trust is eroded,
people will no longer
associate coroners with truth and justice.
So, it has to be stressed
that coroners must not kill.
Only in this way
can this profession
be preserved and honored.
Well said.
Excellent!
I'll put your remarks
in the final chapter
of The Autopsy Chronicles.
[In loving memory of
my father Geng Wushang]
I think Mr. Geng left
the final chapter unfinished
because
he wanted you to be his co-author.
What?
It was you
who first stated
why coroners must not kill.
As Mr. Geng's daughter,
you're responsible to finish this book
for him.
With this book's help,
you will earn great respect
in the coroner profession.
I believe
Mr. Geng intentionally
left this opportunity for you.
Complete the book.
Perhaps its influence will extend
a thousand years into the future.
It may become an essential read
for those who are to enter
the coroner profession.
[In loving memory of
my father Geng Wushang]
The Emperor has ordered
the Coroners' Contest to be cancelled.
That said, since Geng Wushang
and his daughter, Suchan,
made great contributions
by writing The Autopsy Chronicles,
Suchan is specially permitted
to work in the county office
as a designated coroner.
She's removed
from the status of social inferiority,
and her descendants can choose
to be coroners or not
of their own will.
They can also take imperial examinations.
This is wonderful news.
I've also heard of something.
Why are you being so mysterious?
Just say it.
The Emperor planned to hold
the Coroners' Contest
because he read the memorial
you submitted.
The memorial I submitted?
Yes.
Didn't you hand in a memorial
when you came back
from your journey to the west?
Are you indicating
this entire series of murders
was actually caused by me?
I didn't say that.
How dare you, Su Wuming!
That memorial was as much mine as yours.
I stated clearly in it that you and I
wrote that memorial together.
What's this temper tantrum about?
I was trying to say
that the Emperor often reviews
the memorials submitted by you.
What does that mean?
It means in His Majesty's heart,
you, Lu Lingfeng, are very important.
Is that so?
His Majesty asked to see me
in the palace tomorrow.
I don't know what the meeting is for yet.
Something good, I guess.
It definitely is for something good.
I hope so.
[Imperial Polo Ball]
The Yenisei Kirghiz Team scored!
Five to three!
Bravo!
-Bravo!
The Yenisei Kirghiz Team scored!
Five to three!
Our Tang Team isn't even playing.
Why is she so excited?
Look how delighted she is.
That was a great hit.
Natie has scored
three points in a row.
The Yenisei Kirghiz Team scored again!
Six to three!
[Yenisei Kirghiz Team]
Nice play!
[Yenisei Kirghiz Team] [Tulo Team]
The match is over!
Final score: six to three!
The Yenisei Kirghiz Team won!
We won!
The world's greatest polo player!
A warrior of Yenisei Kirghiz!
Truly impressive.
[Yenisei Kirghiz Team] [Tulo Team]
[Peace and prosperity]
I, Minister of Ceremonials,
Pei Mian from Hedong,
[Minister of Ceremonials, Pei Mian]
hereby announce
that 10 days later,
the polo final will be held
between the Tang Team
[Peace and prosperity]
and the Yenisei Kirghiz Team,
which will decide
the champion of this international polo
tournament.
Natie! Natie!
The world's greatest polo player!
What we hated to see
has happened anyway.
Our Tang Team is going to fight
a formidable rival in the final.
Natie
is the younger brother of Nasha,
Khan of Yenisei Kirghiz.
It's said
that he has loved polo since childhood.
Today's match
was a good one.
But in the face of our Tang Team,
they'll surely be losers.
That's for sure.
You officials
of the Bureau of Guest Reception
must see to
the Yenisei Kirghiz's
daily accommodation and meals.
Otherwise, once they lose in the game,
they'll blame us
for not feeding them properly.
This concerns
the etiquette of our Tang Empire.
As you command.
Consider it done, Chief Minister.
This polo tournament
is hosted
by the Court of State Ceremonials,
with assistance from Yongzhou Prefecture.
Given that, Chief Administrator Xiong,
make sure you do your utmost.
Yes, yes.
Grand General, you're responsible
to maintain security
on the day of the final.
Rest assured, Minister Pei.
"The world's greatest polo player"...
This title
was taken by Natie,
a Yenisei Kirghiz person?
That title was just given
by the Yenisei Kirghiz themselves.
After they play the final
against our Tang Team,
their arrogance today
will surely become
a laughingstock in Chang'an.
That's right, Pei.
On the day of the final,
I will personally lead the Tang Team
against the Yenisei Kirghiz Team.
I'll have them know
the Tang Empire is unrivaled
in the world's polo circles.
Lu Lingfeng!
Yes, Your Majesty.
Do you know
why I summoned you to the palace today?
Do you remember the previous
international polo tournament
from four years ago?
It was exactly the great teamwork
between you and I
that turned the tables
for the Tang Team in the final.
We defeated the Tulo Team at last.
You will join me
in the polo game 10 days later
to defeat the Yenisei Kirghiz Team.
Wait.
Your Majesty cannot play this final.
Are you concerned about my safety, Pei?
Don't worry.
With Lu Lingfeng's
close protection for me,
what is there to worry about?
That's not it.
Safety is not the reason
that I'm advising
Your Majesty not to play the final.
Four years ago,
Your Majesty was Prince of Linzi.
It was certainly fine
to gallop across the polo field.
But now,
Your Majesty is the Tang Emperor.
The Yenisei Kirghiz Khan
didn't come to
Chang'an for the games at all.
Therefore, it doesn't comply with
the etiquette or the protocol
for Your Highness to play the final.
Pei,
can't we find a reason
to make an exception?
For example... it allows me
to share joy with the populace?
No.
That's a ridiculous excuse.
Please refrain from doing so,
Your Majesty.
Fine.
Forget what I said.
I am the Emperor of the Tang Empire.
On the day of the final,
I'll simply take the field.
Let's see what Pei Mian can do to me.
I remember Your Majesty once said,
"Though I sit on the imperial throne,
I still uphold the diplomatic protocols
made by the Court of State Ceremonials
and observe the etiquette
respected by all vassals."
I wonder what that means.
How bold of you, Yin.
You cited my own words to lecture me?
I dare not.
Please forgive me, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
a secret message.
Where is it from?
The Yenisei Kirghiz.
Your Majesty,
Grand General of the Right Imperial Guard,
Lu Tong,
requests an urgent audience.
Let him in.
Yes.
Your Majesty,
I received a piece of urgent intelligence.
Say it.
Soon,
some Yenisei Kirghiz spies
will sneak into Chang'an
and make contact
with someone code-named "Wolf,"
who has infiltrated the city.
With the final of the polo tournament
approaching,
I'm worried that they may be plotting
against Your Majesty.
Is the intelligence reliable?
It should be.
What's the source?
My subordinate Li Zhuang
bought it at a high price
from an Intel Stall in the Ghost Market.
Li Zhuang?
If I remember correctly,
you've trained him for years
and designated him
to do intelligence work, right?
Yes.
He's trustworthy.
That said... there are many swindlers
in the Ghost Market.
At the moment,
I think it's better
to assume the threat exists
than to dismiss it.
The key is,
we'll be up against the Yenisei Kirghiz
in the polo tournament final.
The Yenisei Kirghiz...
is the Tang Empire's strong rival.
They've always had rapacious ambitions.
Grand General, come here.
This is...
It's from the Yenisei Kirghiz.
I doubt the validity of it.
So, keep it between us only.
Got it.
Where is it from?
A carrier pigeon
sent by the Yenisei Kirghiz in secret.
[If Your Highness
promises us the land of Tingzhou,
when we attack the Tang borders...]
You've read it?
Yes.
How dare you bring it to me then!
[Crucial Nexus]
The Yenisei Kirghiz
must be out of their minds.
Who are they
to demand the land of Tingzhou?
Cut off all contact with them immediately.
If I ever ascend to the throne,
the first thing I'll do
is to send troops to the Yenisei Kirghiz,
seize their Khan,
and have him brought to Chang'an!
Your Highness, please calm down.
If we cut off
contact with them right away,
they won't attack the borders,
and we can't transfer Lu Tong
out of Chang'an
in the name of letting him
lead troops to fight the enemy.
I'd rather postpone this matter
than accept any terms
of theirs.
Your Highness, please reconsider.
There's nothing to consider!
But word from the palace says
the Imperial Guard
has learned that spies
for the Yenisei Kirghiz
will soon enter Chang'an.
If they are caught,
then the secret of us having contact
with the Yenisei Kirghiz may be disclosed.
What's so scary about that?
Even if this secret is disclosed,
what can the man sitting on the throne now
do to me?
I am the State-guarding Grand Princess
of the Tang Empire.
I will not trade the land of Tang Empire
for anything!
Chancellor Cui.
Go to Yongzhou Prefecture
and bring Lu Lingfeng to me.